<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Harold&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Harold&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 10:53:54 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haroldgao.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life of Pi</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/lifeofpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 10:53:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/lifeofpi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had watched the film adapted by Taiwanese director Ang Lee. So when I found it on the shelf in the hotel at Penang, I chose it to be the next book to read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese podcast recommendations</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:51:51 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Podcast (PODCAST) is a form of audio programs similar to radio stations in ancient early days. Its production cost is lower than video content and higher than text content. Compared to reading text, it is much easier to listen to the podcasts. Compared with watching videos, it is easy for a podcast to get more in -depth and detailed insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the place where the podcast is most attractive to me is to accompany and nourish, just like sitting among a group of people, listening to them chatting, you can feel everyone’s voice and laughter through the sound, and feel the atmosphere of the conversation at the time. It is important that you can find a lot of interesting people through a favorite podcast and open a lot of interesting worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From listening to the monthly radio program updated by Miss F in 15 years in Netease Cloud Music, to listening to &amp;ldquo;Proud Form&amp;rdquo; on Himalayas, and then using a special podcast to use a &amp;ldquo;small universe&amp;rdquo; to listen to a large number of podcasts, I listen to the history of the podcast It has been more than 8 years. The podcast has had a lot of influence on me. &amp;ldquo;The Wind Wind said&amp;rdquo; has contributed that I went to Dali for 2 months after leaving in 2020. Digital tourist -related podcasts have contributed to my resignation in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some podcast programs that sound like you like, maybe you can also find your favorite show. (If there is no special explanation, all podcasts can listen to in the &amp;ldquo;Little Universe&amp;rdquo; APP.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Sinsdoorn: Maitak Awe</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/gtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/gtd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get Things Done&lt;/em&gt; is a self-help book written by David Allen, which introduces some basic methods to arrange your daily tasks so that you can live a productive and stressless life. Here are my takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note on your Bali travel experience</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/bali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/bali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In August 2023, I lived in Ubud, Bali for a month, and I was like [HTTPS://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/wyty2tqthw8zhdkiptl1SQ). More often, just wandering in the paddy fields and houses. This article only summarizes some local life information and gives friends who are interested in traveling to Ubud for a reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also traveling abroad for the first time, and I am traveling alone. As long as I have prepared in advance, I can solve it step by step when I encounter problems. All problems can be solved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My English Learning Story</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/english/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/english/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我现在27岁。 我的第一个英语课程大约是10岁。那时英语不是在小学上教授的课程，通常从中学开始教书。 但是我母亲在星期六找到了一位老师来教我简单的英语单词。 我主要学习了基本词汇，例如数字，几个月和字母。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Study Diary (2)</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At less than 6:30 on Sunday, I woke up from the bed, picked up the mobile phone on the table, checked the matters to be handled today, and waited for the alarm clock at 6:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At less than 7:30, I was already sitting on the bench of the restaurant, carrying a schoolbag, there were scholarship for breakfast, half a bottle of hot boiling water, and a Chinese novel borrowed to me by Taiwan classmates. Finally, Teacher Zelle came in. &amp;ldquo;Wait a while, I drink a cup of coffee.&amp;rdquo; Saying her tearing the coffee powder bag, bent over to push the water coffee in front of the water dispenser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain was crackling outside. Recently, there seems to be a typhoon passing. This week&amp;rsquo;s rain is intermittent. After a while, the slippers under the eaves are poured down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Study Diary (1)</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 30, 2023, Shenzhen, China, in the afternoon of Friday, looked back at a small 10 -square -meter room that had lived for 4 years. There are also movie posters bought by Taobao, and the desktop has been cleaned up. Seeing that it resumed the empty appearance, I felt a little panicked. This small room that had lived for 4 years has no longer belonging to me. In this city, country, and even the planet, I will start a section of a certain place where there is no place. The journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital nomads in &#34;just work, not work&#34;</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Now young people, why don&amp;rsquo;t you want to go to work] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.douban.com/note/655911213/)%22&#34;&gt;https://www.douban.com/note/655911213/)&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;? In February 2018, after watching the first episode of &amp;ldquo;The Round Table&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go to work&amp;rdquo;, Lin An -an office worker who made digital media marketing wrote this text in Douban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She continued to interview a few friends who did not go to work after get off work, and began the interview project &amp;ldquo;100 people who did not go to work.&amp;rdquo; Through the popularity of this topic, Lin An got a lot of media, magazines, and opportunities for business cooperation, which gave her to feed her confidence through writing. At the same time, in order to prevent the instability of text work in early income, she tried to turn her photography hobby into a living method for paying for a contract. Finally, in the summer of 2018, she resigned. For the second month of resignation, her monthly income exceeded the work salary for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a blink of an eye, Lin An has entered the 6th year of the freelance profession. By exploring, transforming, and light entrepreneurship, she is now doing the &amp;ldquo;Liberal Living Room&amp;rdquo; of a free professional community and has her own entrepreneurial team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book &amp;ldquo;Only Working, No Work&amp;rdquo; was published in September 2019. It includes the story of 20 people who do not go to work in &amp;ldquo;100 people who do not go to work&amp;rdquo;, and of course Lin An&amp;rsquo;s own story. In this article, I will share the stories of several partners of the digital nomads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I sell my virtual reality glasses</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/vrglass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/vrglass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At more than 2 am (Beijing time) on June 6, 2023, at the Apple Developer Conference, after the introduction of the new features of iOS, iPados, and MacOS in one hour, the lens turned to a dark lecture hall, a silver -haired Apple company chief of Apple Company Executive Cook, with his slightly old voice, said, &amp;ldquo;There is another product, we have prepared for it for many years.&amp;rdquo; The big screen is dark, and the bright arc outlines a outline of a ski mirror. This is Apple&amp;rsquo;s first virtual reality glasses, Apple Vision Pro.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vivi: After working for three years, I went to Carnegie Mellon to restart my life</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/vivi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/vivi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Editor&amp;rsquo;s click: vivi is my classmate in the character interview class. Seeing her self -introduction, I was attracted to it all at once, and then learned more about her stories about her through Xiaohongshu. Finally, at 11 am in Beijing time, at 8 pm in San Francisco time, crossing half of the earth, we started this online interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023 is the fourth year of Vivi working in the United States. Now she is a product designer in Microsoft. Her Cloudai team is connected to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s new generation of artificial intelligence products to the project of the cloud service platform Azure. The era of a national AI has come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yangshuo Travel Diary</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/yangshuo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/yangshuo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The earliest wanted to go to Yangshuo was to see a Chinese article &amp;ldquo;Lonely Planet&amp;rdquo; in the Youth Hostel of Shaxi Ancient Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the May Day holiday in 2022, I finally went to Yangshuo. Many of the schedules were temporarily arranged, but the people and the people and actually made a wonderful holiday life beyond their expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience of each day is great, so the first half is directly shared this wonderful journey with daily records. The second half will summarize some small experiences for readers who want to travel to Yangshuo and hope to help you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The year of not going to work</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</guid>
      <description>In early July 2020, he got the company&amp;rsquo;s departure certificate. He left the company&amp;rsquo;s building with a small yellow car under the sun in July. There were very few people on the road. The roads were hot and sunny. In late June 2021, a new work unit is about to enter the job, just a heavy rain, at this time the weather is cool. One year passed, and the days</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s start with &#34;The Wedding Banquet&#34;</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/banquet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/banquet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At [HTTPS://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/cxdsqgbl7qn1MTFAZOJHBG), I watched Li An&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Happy Banquet&amp;rdquo; (released in 1993). This is the second time I look at it. When I look at it, I just feel good -looking, interesting, rich. After reading it, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to say, but in the later Yu Yun, some personal feelings were raised.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dali to Shenzhen</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/shenzhen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/shenzhen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon of 2 months ago, before the plane arrived at Dali Airport, he looked out from a small window. It was a mountain and blue sky, and it was a Dali dam built around Erhai Lake. In the evening when I returned to Shenzhen, I looked out of the small window of the plane. It was the real seawater nearly in front of me, and it was the human lighting of the star on the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I am not used to Shenzhen, record my little feelings in the conversion of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to living in Dali</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/dali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/dali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cangshan Erhai Lake is beautiful, but the place where Dali is most attractive is actually its precious community atmosphere. If you want to understand what this community atmosphere is in advance, you may wish to read the book &amp;ldquo;Dali Interview: as if there is a light&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My longing for Dali was influenced by [Jade&amp;rsquo;s Podcast &amp;ldquo;Evening Wind&amp;rdquo;] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.podchaser.com/podcasts/1054935/episodes/e50jade-60754923)&#34;&gt;https://www.podchaser.com/podcasts/1054935/episodes/e50jade-60754923)&lt;/a&gt;. In early 2020, the epidemic was finally promoted to travel from Beijing to Dali, and started a series of podcast programs interviewed by Dali Life. In those days, I struggled in Shenzhen, and often listened to these podcasts in the evening of the weekend, running along the seaside, and at those gentle nights, the other life choices presented in the show gradually moved me. In the end, at the end of 2020, I also came to Dali and lived for 2 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a travel notes, nor will it cover many Dali Internet celebrity punch points. It is a fragment that I like very much in slow travel. It constitutes Dali I yearn for. In two months, in addition to 3 days in Shaxi Ancient Town and Jianchuan Ancient Town in Jianchuan County, I went to Jizi Mountain in Binchuan County to climb the mountain in one day. Surrounding activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第一部分介绍大理吸引我的地方和人，第二部分分享我收集的旅行信息。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
