<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Harold&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Harold&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 08:26:03 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haroldgao.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>English Recommendation 2: Evening Mist Garden &#43; View of Happiness</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/engshare2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 08:26:03 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/engshare2/</guid>
      <description>(This essay is translated from zh-CN)
Author&amp;rsquo;s note : On July 1, 2023, I started my first overseas trip from Hong Kong Airport. A very important goal during the trip was to understand English podcasts. Intensive listening to Chinese podcasts over the past few years has had a huge impact on me. I&amp;rsquo;m curious, what inspiration will the world of English podcasts bring me? I have switched most of my daily information input to English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Recommendation 1: Youth Pi &#43; View of Wealth</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/engshare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 08:26:03 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/engshare/</guid>
      <description>(This essay is translated from zh-CN)
On July 1st this year, I started my first overseas trip from Hong Kong Airport. A very important goal during the trip was to understand English podcasts. Intensive listening to Chinese podcasts over the past few years has had a huge impact on me. I&amp;rsquo;m curious, what inspiration will the world of English podcasts bring me? I have switched most of my daily information input to English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 28, my 4th month of traveling around the world</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:58:08 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear2023/</guid>
      <description>In mid-October 2023, the fourth month of his global travel, Harold spent his 28th birthday in Chiang Mai, a city in northern Thailand. This article serves as a midway review of the gap year, looking back on the experiences, gains, and confusions along the way.
1. Why set out In January 2023, I was celebrating the Spring Festival at my aunt&amp;rsquo;s house at the foot of Huangshan Mountain in Anhui Province.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life of Pi</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/lifeofpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 10:53:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/lifeofpi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had watched the film adapted by Taiwanese director Ang Lee. So when I found it on the shelf in the hotel at Penang, I chose it to be the next book to read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese podcast recommendations</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:51:51 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</guid>
      <description>Podcast is an audio program format similar to ancient radio stations. It costs less to produce than video content and more than text content. Listening to podcasts is much easier than reading text, and it is easier to gain more in-depth and detailed insights by listening to podcasts than watching videos.
For me, the most attractive thing about listening to podcasts is the companionship and nourishment. It’s like sitting among a group of people and listening to them chatting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Things Done: My Take Away</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/gtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/gtd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get Things Done&lt;/em&gt; is a self-help book written by David Allen, which introduces some basic methods to arrange your daily tasks so that you can live a productive and stressless life. Here are my takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bali travel experience notes</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/bali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/bali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In August 2023, I stayed in Ubud, Bali for a month. Just like my stay in Dali, I didn’t check in many famous attractions. , more often than not just wandering around in the rice fields and among the houses. This article just summarizes some local life information to provide a reference for friends who are interested in traveling to Ubud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also my first time to travel abroad, and I am traveling alone. As long as I prepare in advance and solve problems step by step, all problems can be easily solved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My English Learning Story</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/english/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/english/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am 27 years old now. I had my first English course around at the age of 10. At that time English was not a course being taught at elementary school, and it usually was taught starting in middle school. But my mother found a teacher to teach me simple English words on Saturdays. I mainly learned basic vocabulary, such as numbers, months and letters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Study Diary (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just before 6:30 on Sunday morning, I woke up from bed, picked up the phone on the table, checked today’s to-do list, and waited for the 6:30 alarm clock to ring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before 7:30, I was already sitting on a bench in the dining room, carrying a schoolbag. In it were a Snickers bar for breakfast, half a bottle of hot water, and a Chinese novel lent to me by a Taiwanese classmate. Finally, Teacher Zelle walked in and said, &amp;ldquo;Wait a minute, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a cup of coffee.&amp;rdquo; As she said this, she tore open the bag of coffee powder and bent down in front of the water dispenser to get the boiling water to make coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain was pattering heavily outside. It seems that a typhoon has passed by recently, and the rain has been intermittent this week. Sometimes it pours down and wets the slippers under the eaves, and sometimes the sun is shining in the sky and dries the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Study Diary - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 30, 2023, Shenzhen, China, on a Friday afternoon, I looked back at this small 10-square-meter room that I had lived in for 4 years. The room had been emptied, leaving only the bed, wardrobe, desk and chair, and the walls. There are still movie posters bought on Taobao hanging on it, and the tabletop has been cleaned up. Seeing that it was empty again, I felt a little panicked. This small room that I had lived in for 4 years no longer belonged to me. I was about to start a period of no fixed abode in this city, this country, and even this planet. journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nomads in “All Work, No Work”</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</guid>
      <description>“ Why don’t today’s young people want to go to work ?” In February 2018, after watching an episode of &amp;ldquo;Round Table Party&amp;rdquo; titled &amp;ldquo;How to break up if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go to work&amp;rdquo;, Lin An, an office worker who works in digital media marketing, wrote this text on Douban.
She continued her off-duty interviews with several friends who were not working, and began the interview project “100 People Not Working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I sell my virtual reality glasses</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/vrglass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/vrglass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At more than 2 am (Beijing time) on June 6, 2023, at the Apple Developer Conference, after the introduction of the new features of iOS, iPados, and MacOS in one hour, the lens turned to a dark lecture hall, a silver -haired Apple company chief of Apple Company Executive Cook, with his slightly old voice, said, &amp;ldquo;There is another product, we have prepared for it for many years.&amp;rdquo; The big screen is dark, and the bright arc outlines a outline of a ski mirror. This is Apple&amp;rsquo;s first virtual reality glasses, Apple Vision Pro.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vivi: After working for three years, I went to Carnegie Mellon University to restart my life</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/vivi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/vivi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor&amp;rsquo;s note&lt;/strong&gt; : Vivi is my classmate in the character interview class. I was immediately attracted to her when I saw her self-introduction, and then learned more about her story through Xiaohongshu. Finally, at 11 a.m. Beijing time and 8 p.m. San Francisco time, halfway around the world, we started this online interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023 is Vivi&amp;rsquo;s fourth year working in the United States. She is now working as a product designer at Microsoft. Her CloudAI team is integrating Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s new generation artificial intelligence product Copilot into the cloud service platform Azure project. An era of universal AI has arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yangshuo travel diary</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/yangshuo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/yangshuo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first time I wanted to go to Yangshuo was when I saw a Chinese chapter of &amp;ldquo;Lonely Planet&amp;rdquo; in a youth hostel in Shaxi Ancient Town. The book praised the scenery of Yangshuo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the May Day holiday in 2022, I finally went to Yangshuo. Many of the itinerary arrangements were temporary, but the right time, place, people and people actually made for an unexpectedly wonderful holiday life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day&amp;rsquo;s experience was great, so the first half is a daily record to share this wonderful journey. The second half will summarize some experiences for readers who want to travel to Yangshuo, hoping to help you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This year of not working</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</guid>
      <description>In early July 2020, I received the company&amp;rsquo;s resignation certificate and rode a small yellow car out of the company building under the scorching July sun. There were few people on the road, the road was steaming and the sun was shining brightly. In late June 2021, I was about to join a new workplace. There had just been a heavy rain and the weather was cool. One year has passed and the days of not working are coming to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s start with &#34;The Wedding Banquet&#34;</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/banquet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/banquet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched &amp;ldquo;The Wedding Banquet&amp;rdquo; (released in 1993) directed by Ang Lee at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/cxDsQGbl7QN1MtFazOjhbg&#34;&gt;Movie Viewing Exchange Meeting&lt;/a&gt;. This is my second time watching it, and when I watched it I just thought it was beautiful, interesting, and rich. I didn’t know what to say just after reading it, but in the aftermath, I had some personal thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dali to Shenzhen</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/shenzhen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/shenzhen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon of 2 months ago, before the plane arrived at Dali Airport, he looked out from a small window. It was a mountain and blue sky, and it was a Dali dam built around Erhai Lake. In the evening when I returned to Shenzhen, I looked out of the small window of the plane. It was the real seawater nearly in front of me, and it was the human lighting of the star on the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I am not used to Shenzhen, record my little feelings in the conversion of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dali Living Guide</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/dali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/dali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cangshan Mountain and Erhai Lake are beautiful, but what attracts me most about Dali is actually its precious community atmosphere. If you want to know in advance what this kind of community atmosphere is, you might as well read the book &amp;ldquo;Interviews with Dali: As if There is Light&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My yearning for Dali was deeply influenced by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.podchaser.com/podcasts/1054935/episodes/e50jade-60754923&#34;&gt;Jade’s podcast &amp;ldquo;Evening Breeze&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; . The epidemic in early 2020 finally pushed Jade to travel from Beijing to Dali and started a series of podcasts interviewing people living in Dali. In those days, I was struggling in Shenzhen. I would often listen to these podcasts and run along the seaside on weekend evenings. In those tender nights, I was gradually moved by the different life choices presented in the program. Finally, at the end of 2020, I also came to Dali and stayed for 2 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a travelogue, nor does it cover many of Dali’s internet celebrity check-in points. It is completely the fragments that I like very much in slow travel, and it constitutes the Dali that I yearn for. In the past two months, except for three days in Shaxi Ancient Town and Jianchuan Ancient Town in Jianchuan County, one day hiking in Jizu Mountain in Binchuan County, and one day cycling around the Erhai Lake, I spent most of my time in Dali Ancient Town. Surrounding activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part introduces the places and people that attract me to Dali, and the second part shares the travel information I collected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
