<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on Harold&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://haroldgao.com/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on Harold&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haroldgao.com/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bali travel experience notes</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/bali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/bali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In August 2023, I stayed in Ubud, Bali for a month. Just like my stay in Dali, I didn’t check in many famous attractions. , more often than not just wandering around in the rice fields and among the houses. This article just summarizes some local life information to provide a reference for friends who are interested in traveling to Ubud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also my first time to travel abroad, and I am traveling alone. As long as I prepare in advance and solve problems step by step, all problems can be easily solved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Study Diary (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just before 6:30 on Sunday morning, I woke up from bed, picked up the phone on the table, checked today’s to-do list, and waited for the 6:30 alarm clock to ring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before 7:30, I was already sitting on a bench in the dining room, carrying a schoolbag. In it were a Snickers bar for breakfast, half a bottle of hot water, and a Chinese novel lent to me by a Taiwanese classmate. Finally, Teacher Zelle walked in and said, &amp;ldquo;Wait a minute, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a cup of coffee.&amp;rdquo; As she said this, she tore open the bag of coffee powder and bent down in front of the water dispenser to get the boiling water to make coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain was pattering heavily outside. It seems that a typhoon has passed by recently, and the rain has been intermittent this week. Sometimes it pours down and wets the slippers under the eaves, and sometimes the sun is shining in the sky and dries the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Study Diary - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/philippines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 30, 2023, Shenzhen, China, on a Friday afternoon, I looked back at this small 10-square-meter room that I had lived in for 4 years. The room had been emptied, leaving only the bed, wardrobe, desk and chair, and the walls. There are still movie posters bought on Taobao hanging on it, and the tabletop has been cleaned up. Seeing that it was empty again, I felt a little panicked. This small room that I had lived in for 4 years no longer belonged to me. I was about to start a period of no fixed abode in this city, this country, and even this planet. journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dali to Shenzhen</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/shenzhen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/shenzhen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon of 2 months ago, before the plane arrived at Dali Airport, he looked out from a small window. It was a mountain and blue sky, and it was a Dali dam built around Erhai Lake. In the evening when I returned to Shenzhen, I looked out of the small window of the plane. It was the real seawater nearly in front of me, and it was the human lighting of the star on the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I am not used to Shenzhen, record my little feelings in the conversion of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dali Living Guide</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/dali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/dali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cangshan Mountain and Erhai Lake are beautiful, but what attracts me most about Dali is actually its precious community atmosphere. If you want to know in advance what this kind of community atmosphere is, you might as well read the book &amp;ldquo;Interviews with Dali: As if There is Light&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My yearning for Dali was deeply influenced by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.podchaser.com/podcasts/1054935/episodes/e50jade-60754923&#34;&gt;Jade’s podcast &amp;ldquo;Evening Breeze&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; . The epidemic in early 2020 finally pushed Jade to travel from Beijing to Dali and started a series of podcasts interviewing people living in Dali. In those days, I was struggling in Shenzhen. I would often listen to these podcasts and run along the seaside on weekend evenings. In those tender nights, I was gradually moved by the different life choices presented in the program. Finally, at the end of 2020, I also came to Dali and stayed for 2 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a travelogue, nor does it cover many of Dali’s internet celebrity check-in points. It is completely the fragments that I like very much in slow travel, and it constitutes the Dali that I yearn for. In the past two months, except for three days in Shaxi Ancient Town and Jianchuan Ancient Town in Jianchuan County, one day hiking in Jizu Mountain in Binchuan County, and one day cycling around the Erhai Lake, I spent most of my time in Dali Ancient Town. Surrounding activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part introduces the places and people that attract me to Dali, and the second part shares the travel information I collected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
