<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nomadism on Harold&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://haroldgao.com/categories/nomadism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nomadism on Harold&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:51:51 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haroldgao.com/categories/nomadism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chinese podcast recommendations</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:51:51 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</guid>
      <description>Podcast is an audio program format similar to ancient radio stations. It costs less to produce than video content and more than text content. Listening to podcasts is much easier than reading text, and it is easier to gain more in-depth and detailed insights by listening to podcasts than watching videos.
For me, the most attractive thing about listening to podcasts is the companionship and nourishment. It’s like sitting among a group of people and listening to them chatting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nomads in “All Work, No Work”</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</guid>
      <description>“ Why don’t today’s young people want to go to work ?” In February 2018, after watching an episode of &amp;ldquo;Round Table Party&amp;rdquo; titled &amp;ldquo;How to break up if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go to work&amp;rdquo;, Lin An, an office worker who works in digital media marketing, wrote this text on Douban.
She continued her off-duty interviews with several friends who were not working, and began the interview project “100 People Not Working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The year of not going to work</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</guid>
      <description>In early July 2020, I received my resignation certificate from the company and rode a small yellow car out of the company building under the scorching July sun. There were few people on the road, the road was steaming and the sun was shining brightly. In late June 2021, I was about to join a new workplace. There had just been a heavy rain and the weather was cool. One year has passed in a flash, and the days of not working are coming to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
