<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nomadism on Harold&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://haroldgao.com/categories/nomadism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nomadism on Harold&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:51:51 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haroldgao.com/categories/nomadism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chinese podcast recommendations</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:51:51 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Podcast is an audio program format similar to ancient radio stations. It costs less to produce than video content and more than text content. Listening to podcasts is much easier than reading text, and it is easier to gain more in-depth and detailed insights by listening to podcasts than watching videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the most attractive thing about listening to podcasts is the companionship and nourishment. It’s like sitting among a group of people and listening to them chatting. You can feel everyone’s voice and smile through the sound, and feel the atmosphere of the conversation at that time. What’s more, The important thing is that you can discover a lot of interesting people and open up a lot of interesting worlds through a favorite podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from listening to Ms. F’s monthly updated radio program on NetEase Cloud Music in 2015, to listening to “Be Fortunate” on Himalaya, and then to listening to a lot of podcasts using the dedicated podcast application “Little Universe” in 2019, my history of listening to podcasts It&amp;rsquo;s been over 8 years. Podcasts have had a lot of influence on me. &amp;ldquo;Speaking of the Evening Breeze&amp;rdquo; prompted me to travel to Dali for 2 months after leaving my job in 2020. Digital nomad-related podcasts prompted me to quit my job and start a gap year travel in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I would like to share with you some podcast programs that I have heard very much, maybe you can also find your favorite program among them. (Unless otherwise specified, all podcasts can be listened to in the &amp;ldquo;Little Universe&amp;rdquo; APP.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital nomads in &#34;Only Working for Your Own, Not for A Company&#34;</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.douban.com/note/655911213/&#34;&gt;Why don’t today’s young people want to go to work&lt;/a&gt;”? In February 2018, after watching an episode of &amp;ldquo;Round Table Party&amp;rdquo; titled &amp;ldquo;How to break up if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go to work&amp;rdquo;, Lin An, an office worker who works in digital media marketing, wrote this text on Douban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She continued her off-duty interviews with several friends who were not working, and began the interview project “100 People Not Working.” Through the popularity of this topic, Lin An received many invitations from media and magazines, as well as opportunities for business cooperation, which gave her the confidence to support herself through writing. At the same time, in order to prevent the instability of her early income from writing work, she tried to turn her photography hobby into a means of making a living by paying for photo shoots. Finally, in the summer of 2018, she resigned. In the second month after her resignation, her monthly income exceeded her working salary for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the blink of an eye, Lin An has entered her 6th year of freelancing. Through exploration, transformation, and light entrepreneurship, she is now working full-time in the freelancing community &amp;ldquo;Freedom Living Room&amp;rdquo; and has her own entrepreneurial team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book &amp;ldquo;Only Working for Your Own, Not for A Company&amp;rdquo; was published in September 2019. It collects the stories of 20 people who don&amp;rsquo;t work in &amp;ldquo;100 People Who Don&amp;rsquo;t Work&amp;rdquo;, and of course Lin An&amp;rsquo;s own story. In this article, I will share the stories of several of my fellow digital nomads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The year of not going to work</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</guid>
      <description>In early July 2020, I received my resignation certificate from the company and rode a small yellow car out of the company building under the scorching July sun. There were few people on the road, the road was steaming and the sun was shining brightly. In late June 2021, I was about to join a new workplace. There had just been a heavy rain and the weather was cool. One year has passed in a flash, and the days of not working are coming to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
