<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nomadism on Harold&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://haroldgao.com/categories/nomadism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nomadism on Harold&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:51:51 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haroldgao.com/categories/nomadism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chinese podcast recommendations</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:51:51 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Podcast (PODCAST) is a form of audio programs similar to radio stations in ancient early days. Its production cost is lower than video content and higher than text content. Compared to reading text, it is much easier to listen to the podcasts. Compared with watching videos, it is easy for a podcast to get more in -depth and detailed insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the place where the podcast is most attractive to me is to accompany and nourish, just like sitting among a group of people, listening to them chatting, you can feel everyone’s voice and laughter through the sound, and feel the atmosphere of the conversation at the time. It is important that you can find a lot of interesting people through a favorite podcast and open a lot of interesting worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From listening to the monthly radio program updated by Miss F in 15 years in Netease Cloud Music, to listening to &amp;ldquo;Proud Form&amp;rdquo; on Himalayas, and then using a special podcast to use a &amp;ldquo;small universe&amp;rdquo; to listen to a large number of podcasts, I listen to the history of the podcast It has been more than 8 years. The podcast has had a lot of influence on me. &amp;ldquo;The Wind Wind said&amp;rdquo; has contributed that I went to Dali for 2 months after leaving in 2020. Digital tourist -related podcasts have contributed to my resignation in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some podcast programs that sound like you like, maybe you can also find your favorite show. (If there is no special explanation, all podcasts can listen to in the &amp;ldquo;Little Universe&amp;rdquo; APP.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital nomads in &#34;just work, not work&#34;</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/digitalnomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Now young people, why don&amp;rsquo;t you want to go to work] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.douban.com/note/655911213/)%22&#34;&gt;https://www.douban.com/note/655911213/)&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;? In February 2018, after watching the first episode of &amp;ldquo;The Round Table&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go to work&amp;rdquo;, Lin An -an office worker who made digital media marketing wrote this text in Douban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She continued to interview a few friends who did not go to work after get off work, and began the interview project &amp;ldquo;100 people who did not go to work.&amp;rdquo; Through the popularity of this topic, Lin An got a lot of media, magazines, and opportunities for business cooperation, which gave her to feed her confidence through writing. At the same time, in order to prevent the instability of text work in early income, she tried to turn her photography hobby into a living method for paying for a contract. Finally, in the summer of 2018, she resigned. For the second month of resignation, her monthly income exceeded the work salary for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a blink of an eye, Lin An has entered the 6th year of the freelance profession. By exploring, transforming, and light entrepreneurship, she is now doing the &amp;ldquo;Liberal Living Room&amp;rdquo; of a free professional community and has her own entrepreneurial team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book &amp;ldquo;Only Working, No Work&amp;rdquo; was published in September 2019. It includes the story of 20 people who do not go to work in &amp;ldquo;100 people who do not go to work&amp;rdquo;, and of course Lin An&amp;rsquo;s own story. In this article, I will share the stories of several partners of the digital nomads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The year of not going to work</title>
      <link>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiangaoole@gmail.com (Harold Gao)</author>
      <guid>https://haroldgao.com/post/gapyear/</guid>
      <description>In early July 2020, he got the company&amp;rsquo;s departure certificate. He left the company&amp;rsquo;s building with a small yellow car under the sun in July. There were very few people on the road. The roads were hot and sunny. In late June 2021, a new work unit is about to enter the job, just a heavy rain, at this time the weather is cool. One year passed, and the days</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
